Guide to Miscellaneous Financial Materials Concerning Power Companies Operating in the North American West
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Miscellaneous financial materials concerning power companies operating in the North American West
1892-1945
Ndy54
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
(23 boxes)
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning power companies operating in the North American West. Examples of these documents include company correspondence, letters and notices to the stockholders, maps, company profiles and charters, booklets of photographs, press releases, newspaper clippings, earnings statements, balance sheets, prospectuses, reports to the stockholders, proxy statements, stock and bond offerings, applications to the Securities and Exchange Commission, trust and mortgage indentures, protective and consolidation agreements, subscription agreements, legal briefs and other court documents. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Most of these financial materials were part of a collection acquired by Yale in 1922 from William H. Brown of West Haven, Conn. The collection, initially called the William H. Brown Statistical Library, numbered some 23,000 documents and covered the years 1890 to 1917. The collection was merged with similar materials already in the University Library and later expanded by gifts from Brown and others to become what is now known as the William H. Brown Collection.
Scope and Contents
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning power companies operating in the North American West. Examples of these documents include company correspondence, letters and notices to the stockholders, maps, company profiles and charters, booklets of photographs, press releases, newspaper clippings, earnings statements, balance sheets, prospectuses, reports to the stockholders, proxy statements, stock and bond offerings, applications to the Securities and Exchange Commission, trust and mortgage indentures, protective and consolidation agreements, subscription agreements, legal briefs and other court documents. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Arrangement
Files are arranged first by region, i.e. Canada and the United States, and then alphabetically by company name.
Electric power production -- West (U.S.); Electric power production -- Canada, Western; Electric industries -- West (U.S.); Electric industries -- Canada, Western; Trust indentures -- Specimens.; Proxy statements -- Specimens.; Financial statements -- Specimens.; William H. Brown Collection
- Manitoba Power Company, Limited, 1921-1927; Ndy54 C1 +M31; (10 documents) (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
- Western Canada Power Company, Limited, 1915-1916; Ndy54 C1 +W52; (4 documents) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Arkansas Central Power Company, 1923-1924; Ndy54 U2 +Ar3; (7 documents) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Arkansas Light and Power Company, 1914-1924; Ndy54 U2 +Ar4; (4 documents) (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
- Arkansas-Missouri Power Company, 1924-1925; Ndy54 U2 +Ar43; (4 documents) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Arkansas Power and Light Company, 1926-1933; Ndy54 U2 +Ar47; (8 documents) (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
- Baton Rouge Electric Company, 1909-1937; Ndy54 U2 +B31; (10 documents) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Billings and Eastern Montana Power Company, 1908-1912; Ndy54 U2 +B49; (4 documents) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Boise-Payette River Electric Power Company, 1901-1915; Ndy54 U2 +B63; (3 documents) (Box 14, Folder 1)
- California Oregon Power Company, 1921-1939; Ndy54 U2 +C12; (10 documents) (Box 14, Folder 2-3)
- Central Colorado Power Company, 1912-1913; Ndy54 U2 +C33; (3 documents) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Central Iowa Power and Light Company, 1914-1924; Ndy54 U2 +C35; (4 documents) (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
- Dallas Power and Light Company, 1917-1937; Ndy54 U2 +D16; (26 documents) (Box 14, Folder 4-5)
- Dubuque Electric Company, 1923; Ndy54 U2 +D85; (4 documents) (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Edison Electric Company, 1902; Ndy54 U2 +Ed29; (8 documents) (Box 14, Folder 6)
- El Paso Electric Company (Texas), 1902-1925; Ndy54 U2 +EL1; (10 documents) (Box 3, Folder 4)
- El Paso Electric Company (New Jersey), 1917-1920; Ndy54 U2 +EL12; (6 documents) (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Electric Power and Light Corporation, 1925-1946; Ndy54 U2 +EL3; (13 documents) (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Empire District Electric Company, 1909-1927; Ndy54 U2 +Em65; (4 documents) (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
- Feather River Power Company, 1925; Ndy54 U2 +F31; (2 documents) (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Galveston Electric Company, 1905-1932; Ndy54 U2 +G125; (4 documents) (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Houghton County Electric Light Company, 1902-1920; Ndy54 U2 +H81; (4 documents) (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Houston Lighting & Power Company, 1902-1944; Ndy54 U2 +H82; (15 documents) (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
- Idaho-Oregon Light and Power Company, 1907-1914; Ndy54 U2 +Id2; (25 documents) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Idaho Power Company, 1917-1944; Ndy54 U2 +Id3; (9 documents) (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
- Interstate Power Company (Delaware), 1924-1927; Ndy54 U2 +In9; (8 documents) (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
- Interstate Power Company (of Wisconsin), 1924; Ndy54 U2 +In92; (2 documents) (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Iowa Light, Heat and Power Company, 1916-1921; Ndy54 U2 +Io92; (2 documents) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Iowa Power and Light Company, 1928; Ndy54 U2 +Io94; (3 documents) (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Kansas City Light and Power Company, 1915; Ndy54 U2 +K128; (3 documents) (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Kansas City Power and Light Company, 1922-1928; Ndy54 U2 +K13; (19 documents) (Box 16, Folder 3-4)
- Kansas Electric Power Company, 1922-1939; Ndy54 U2 +K14; (9 documents) (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Keokuk Electric Company, 1918-1925; Ndy54 U2 +K43; (3 documents) (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Madison River Power Company, 1905; Ndy54 U2 +M26; (2 documents) (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Melones Dam Hydro-Electric Power Development, 1925; Ndy54 U2 +M49; (2 documents) (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Minneapolis General Electric Company, 1899-1914; Ndy54 U2 +M66; (12 documents) (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Minnesota Power & Light Company, 1906-1936; Ndy54 U2 +M675; (19 documents) (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
  Scope and Contents
  Included are documents from the Duluth Edison Electric Company.
- Montana Power Company, 1913-1928; Ndy54 U2 +M76; (13 documents) (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Montana Power Transmission Company, 1899-1910; Ndy54 U2 +M762; (4 documents) (Box 8, Folder 1)
- National Electric Power Company, 1925-1928; Ndy54 U2 +N19; (4 documents) (Box 8, Folder 2)
- National Securities Corporation, 1917-1919; Ndy54 U2 +N23; (18 documents) (Box 8, Folder 3)
- North American Edison Company, 1922-1928; Ndy54 U2 +N79; (16 documents) (Box 17, Folder 3-4)
- Northern Colorado Power Company, 1913; Ndy54 U2 +N81; (3 documents) (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Northwestern Electric Company, 1915; Ndy54 U2 +N85; (7 documents) (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Omaha Electric Light and Power Company, 1903-1905; Ndy54 U2 +Om15; (3 documents) (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Otter Tail Power Company (Delaware), 1925-1926; Ndy54 U2 +Ot8; (2 documents) (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Ozark Power and Water Company, 1912; Ndy54 U2 +Oz2; (4 documents) (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Pacific Coast Power Company, 1910-1911; Ndy54 U2 +P125; (3 documents) (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Pacific Light & Power Corporation, 1907-1916; Ndy54 U2 +P13; (13 documents) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  Included are documents from the Pacific Light & Power Company.
- Portland General Electric Company, 1892-1908; Ndy54 U2 +P826; (8 documents) (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
- Pacific Northwest Public Service Company, 1906-1934; Ndy54 U2 +P83; (85 documents) (Box 18, Folder 1-6)
  Included are documents from the Portland Railway, Light and Power Company and the Portland Electric Power Company.
- Puget Sound Power Company, 1903-1904; Ndy54 U2 +P97; (2 documents) (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Salem Electric Lighting Company, 1922; Ndy54 U2 +Sa2; (1 document) (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Sierra and San Francisco Power Company, 1909-1914; Ndy54 U2 +Si2; (5 documents) (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Southern California Edison Company, 1909-1945; Ndy54 U2 +So7
  - Financial history, 1909-1945; (79 documents) (Box 19, Folder 1-5)
  - Economic aspects, 1916-1937; (7 documents) (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Southern Colorado Power Company, 1918-1925; Ndy54 U2 +So73; (13 documents) (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Southwest Power Company, 1924; Ndy54 U2 +So9; (4 documents) (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Stanislaus Power Development, 1908-1909; Ndy54 U2 +St2; (3 documents) (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Texas Power & Light Company, 1912-1926; Ndy54 U2 +T31; (11 documents) (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
- Union Electric Light and Power Company (St. Louis, Missouri), 1902-1943; Ndy54 U2 +Un3; (17 documents) (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
  Includes a pamphlet on the Bagnell Dam.
- Union Electric Light and Power Company of Illinois, 1923?-1924; Ndy54 U2 +Un31; (5 documents) (Box 21, Folder 3)
- United Light and Power Company, 1911-1940; Ndy54 U2 +Un6; (22 documents) (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
- United Missouri River Power Company, 1906-1908; Ndy54 U2 +Un67; (2 documents) (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Utah Light and Traction Company, 1914-1922; Ndy54 U2 +Ut15; (7 documents) (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Utah Power and Light Company, 1914-1941; Ndy54 U2 +Ut2; (12 documents) (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
- Washington Water Power Company, 1899-1939; Ndy54 U2 +W27
  - Financial history, 1899-1926; (22 documents) (Box 22, Folder 3-4)
  - Economic aspects, 1910-1939; (5 documents) (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Includes one small and two large booklets of photographs.
- Western Power Company, 1913-1915; Ndy54 U2 +W54; (5 documents) (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Western Power Corporation, 1921-1926; Ndy54 U2 +W542; (6 documents) (Box 12, Folder 4-5)